# Denis T. - Professional Software Engineer

dev@denis-it.com

### **SUMMARY**

Full-stack software engineer with 9+ years of experience.

I mostly excited about functional programming, Scala and its ecosystem (Scalaz, Cats, Shapeless, Akka, Slick, Doobie, etc.), have good problems solving and projects responsibility skills. I am learning and evolving every day to provide actual and high-level results to the customers. I follow T-shaped skills model: besides Scala and its environment I am keeping up in C and Javascript / Node.js trends as well so can start working with them pretty quickly. I read news, listen podcasts and watch videos about different technologies to have wide area of thought (Perl, PHP, Python, Rust). Free to use Linux, Mac OS or Windows and ready to work with Git, AWS, Jenkins, Circle, Bugzilla, Redmine, Jira, Bamboo, Trello, GitHub, BitBucket and other commonly used services.

#### SKILLS

- JVM: Scala, Java SE, JavaFX, Android
- C/C++: Desktop, Embedded, Boost, Qt
- Python: IPython, SciPy, PyQt, PySide
- Frontend: HTML 5, CSS 3, ECMA 6, Angular 4
- Backend: Docker, AWS, Kubernetes, Node.js, Perl, PHP
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, CouchDB, DynamoDB
- Continious Integration: Jenkins, Bamboo
- Testing: TDD, BDD
- E-Commerce: OpenCart, WooCommerce
- Tools: Git, Vim, Bash, ADR
- Agile: Scrum, Kanban
- Languages: English (conversational), Russian (native)

## **EXPERIENCE**

IBTrader Oct 2017 - Current

Platform for automated trading using Interactive Brokers API Scala Developer

- Backend development with Scala and Akka Streams

- Documentation writing
- Working in a distributed team

```
[ Scala | Akka | Cats | Shapeless ]
```

VATBox Ltd. May 2017 - Current

Global cloud-based provider of automated VAT recovery Scala Developer

- Projects leading and responsibility
- Backend development with Scala, Akka and Slick
- Database schema development
- Projects deployment on AWS using Kubernetes
- Documentation writing
- Working in a distributed team

```
https://vatbox.com/
[ Scala | Slick | MySQL | Docker | Kubernetes ]
```

FXEmpire Nov 2017 - Dec 2017

Custom datafeed for TradingView Charting Library Node.js Developer

- Development of Node.js Rest API service using Express
- Working with Mongo DB using Mongoose

```
https://www.fxempire.com/
[ Node.js | Express | Mongo | Mongoose ]
```

### FabLab61 Booking Bot

Oct 2016 - Feb 2017

Telegram bot for easy booking of FabLab resources (pet project) Lead Software Engineer

- Project architecture and development

```
https://github.com/FabLab61/bookingbot
[ Perl | Telegram | Docker | Google Calendar API ]
```

#### **Mountain Interactive Inc.**

Dec 2016 - Feb 2017

Stockscores web site development

#### Software Engineer

- Integration of TradingView Charting Library

```
http://mountaininteractive.ca/
[ JS | Node.js | Docker ]
```

Self-employed

Feb 2016 - Jul 2016

Online pet store deployment and development (now closed)

Founder & Software Engineer

```
[ PHP | MySQL | WooCommerce | OpenCart ]
```

**Boxy POS** Jan 2015 - Dec 2015

Free point of sale for restaurants & coffee shops Software Engineer

- Desktop software development with JavaFX
- Android software development with Java
- CouchDB interaction development
- Jenkins CI deployment and support

```
https://www.boxypos.com/
[ Java | JavaFX | Android | CouchDB | Jenkins | AWS ]
```

# **TradingView**

Dec 2011 - Dec 2014

Network where active traders exchange ideas to maximize profit Software Engineer

- Frontend development with HTML, CSS and JS
- Backend development with Java, Python and Node.js
- Specialized language development with Java and ANTLR

```
https://tradingview.com/
[ HTML | JS | Java | Node.js | Python | Jenkins | Docker | Scrum ]
```

RoastLog Feb 2012 - Jan 2013

Software that helps to control coffee roasting process Software Engineer

- Desktop application development with Python and PyQt binding

```
https://roastlog.com/
```

[ Python | PyQt ]

eSignal Jul 2010 - Nov 2011

Desktop stock charting software and trading platform Software Engineer

- Chart module development
- Statistics gathering subsystem development, deployment and support

http://www.esignal.com/

[ C++ | Qt 4 | Java | MySQL | Jenkins | Scrum ]

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Don State Technical University**

Sep 2005 - Jul 2010

http://www.donstu.ru/en/

Bachelor's degree in computer techniques and automatized systems software, diploma with mark of distinction.

## **CONTACTS**

**Location:** Rostov-on-Don, Russia

Website: http://denis-it.com
Email: dev@denis-it.com

GitHub: @denis-it
Telegram: @denis\_it
LinkedIn: @denis-it

Twitter: @denis\_it\_com

# **METAINFO**

**Updated:** Jan 22, 2018